Alejandro Núñez Pérez

 • Granada, Spain
 • ☑ alejnp@proton.me
 • ☐ linkedin.com/in/alejnp
 • ☐ github.com/alxe

About Me _____

Hello! I'm Alejandro, a Software Engineer with over five years of experience across multiple roles and a hunger for learning new things.

When it comes to work, I am most interested in information transformation pipelines, distributed systems, and knowledge sharing.

Personally, my hobbies include finances, anything related to maps, and board games.

Skills and Credentials _____

Customer Support Veteran: Extensive experience in managing customer expectations, providing technical solutions, and ensuring customer satisfaction in high-pressure scenarios

Software Development Expertise: Well-versed in Java, Python, and C/C++ development, testing, packaging and distribution for diverse projects and applications

Quality Assurance Focus: Strong advocate for test-first and quality-oriented development, with the ability to adapt and balance quality considerations against project constraints

DevOps and CI/CD Pipelines: Experienced in designing, building, and maintaining CI/CD pipelines to streamline software quality and delivery processes

Professional Experience _____

Senior Software Engineer, Real-Time Innovations – Hybrid (Granada or Remote) Apr 2024 – present Part of the API, later GPP development teams focused on the Connext Professional products.

- · Maintained an internal, distributed testing Python framework for RTI products.
- Retrofitted the Java API while keeping backwards compatibility, reduced the number of known memory leaks by >90%.
- Developed a new internal web server for storing and visualizing performance data using FastAPI, with a MongoDB database backend.

Software Engineer, Real-Time Innovations – Hybrid (Granada or Remote)

Nov 2019 – Apr 2024

Part of the Support team, providing low-level, technical support to worldwide customers across multiple industry verticals, with a focus on the EMEA and APAC regions.

- Resolved customer time-sensitive escalations on critical deployments.
- · Maintained multiple branches of support releases, built and delivered patches.
- · Led newcomers through onboarding, taught soft and hard skills.

Education

MBA Ediae, Cámara de Comercio, Business – Granada, Spain

Nov 2024 – present

General MBA focused on wide-area knowledge of managing a business, including Strategy, Marketing
and Finances.

- **BS** Universidad de Granada, Computer Science Granada, Spain Sept 2015 Sept 2019 Basics of Computer Science, including Algorithm Design, Data Structures, Networking and Distributed Systems.
 - · Honors in Modern Multi-paradigm Programming.